A metric that is a special application of the Sharpe ratio is the information ratio.
夏普比率的一个特殊应用指标是信息比率
Recall that we are separating known factors as risk factors,
我们将已知因子称为风险因子
which drive the variants of stocks and Alpha factors which
它可以解释股票的方差
drive portfolio returns after neutralizing to those risk factors.
Alpha 因子是指中性化这些风险因子之后带来投资组合收益率的因子
The return driven by risk factors is the systematic return,
风险因子带来的收益率称为系统收益率
whereas the return driven by
在消除风险因子的影响之后
the Alpha factors after taking out the effect of risk factors,
Alpha 因子带来的收益率
well, this is the specific return.
称为特有收益率
The specific return is also referred to as the residual return
特有收益率也称为剩余收益率
because it is the residual amount of return that
因为它是去除系统收益率之后
remains after taking out the systematic return.
剩余的收益率
The information ratio is the Sharpe ratio applied to the specific return.
信息比率是应用到特有收益率上的夏普比率
So, it's the average specific return divided by its standard deviation annualized.
所以它等于平均特有收益率除以标准差并年化后的值
The information ratio can be interpreted as the Sharpe ratio that
信息比率可以看作
measures the performance that the fund manager contributes to the portfolio.
衡量基金经理对投资组合的贡献业绩的夏普比率
Note that in the context of what we're doing in this lesson,
注意 在这节课的背景之下
that is Alpha modeling,
即 Alpha 建模
we are creating a market and common factor neutral portfolio.
我们要创建一个市场和共同因子中性投资组合
Note that in this case,
在这种情形下
the Sharpe ratio equals the information ratio.
夏普比率等于信息比率
We simply introduced the term information ratio
介绍信息比率这个术语
here because you will see it often in academic literature.
是因为你将经常在学术论文中见到这个词
As I stated previously,
正如我之前提到的
the most important metric in evaluating an Alpha factor and
衡量 Alpha 因子以及最终衡量交易策略或基金的
ultimately a trading strategy or fund is the Sharpe ratio.
最重要指标是夏普比率
So, some good advice might be, okay,
有些建议可能直接说
just create Alpha strategies with high Sharpe ratios.
创建夏普比率很高的 Alpha 策略
That advice though is pretty useless because it's descriptive not proscriptive.
但是这种建议根本没用
In other words, it tells us what we want to achieve,
因为它只是告诉我们要实现什么目标
but it says nothing about how to get there.
但是完全没告诉我们如何实现
So, how do we actually create high Sharpe Ratio strategies?
那么如何创建夏普比率很高的策略呢？
Well, the fundamental law of active management gives us some insight.
主动管理基本法则可以给出一些提示
From a philosophical standpoint,
从哲学的角度来看
perhaps the most important thing you will learn in
或许你在这节课能学到的
this program is the following relationship;
最重要的知识是以下公式
IR equals IC times the square root of B.
IR = IC * √B￣
This comes from the seminal work a Richard Grinold,
这个公式来自 Richard Grinold 的开创性著作
which is aptly titled,
《主动管理基本法则》
the Fundamental Law of Active Management.
命名很贴切
This is further detailed in the subsequent book by both Richard Grinold
Richard Grinold 和 Ronald Khan 之后合著的
and Ronald Khan titled, Active Portfolio Management.
《主动投资组合管理》一书详细讲解了这个公式
By the way, this formula IR equals IC times the square root of
顺便提下 IR = IC * √B￣ 这个公式
B sometimes referred to as the E equals MC squared of finance.
有时候称为金融领域的 E=MC^2
I just want to make a point about this formula.
关于这个公式需要注意一点
This result is based on some simplifying assumptions and should be thought of as a guide.
结果基于一些简化的假设并且应该被视作指导
It would be more correct to say that IR is
更准确的说法是
proportional to IC times the square root of B as opposed to equal.
IR 与 IC * √B￣ 成比例 而不是相等
This is not a formula we will use directly.
我们并不直接使用该公式
Meaning, we don't actually use it to make calculations.
也就是并不直接根据它计算值
Rather, we use this identity to direct how we structure our investment process.
而是指导我们构建投资流程
Also, don't worry if the relationship between IR, IC,
如果你觉得 IR IC 和 B 之间的关系
and B doesn't look obvious to you as it's not supposed to be.
看起来不明显 也没关系 本来就不明显
If you're interested in the derivation,
如果你想知道推导过程
you can check out the original paper or the book by Grinold and Kahn.
请参阅原始论文或 Grinold 和 Kahn 合著的图书
I haven't defined what IR, IC,
我还没有解释
and B mean in the context of this relationship.
IR IC 和 B 的含义
But stay tuned, it's coming up.
稍后会讲解的 敬请期待